### **DANIEL BRYAN**

email danbryan80@gmail.com

#### REMOTE DEVOPS ENGINEER

I am a creative minded individual with 20 years of experience in information technology. I'm accomplished in infrastructure, research, and security. I am passionate about cloud technologies and automation. I'm extremely experienced in solutions engineering and troubleshooting. I'm confident in my ability to lead and communicate with others. I have an exceptional understanding how technologies relate to one another and enjoy solving complex technical problems. P.S. I'm recently interested in blockchain!

#### **TOP TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Linux, Amazon Web Services, Go, Kubernetes, Bash, Salt-Stack, PKI, Research

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

September/2018 – PRESENT, Toptal Freelance DevOps Engineer

# October/2016 – PRESENT, Stratus Solutions Senior DevOps Engineer

- Automated multi-account AWS infrastructure using terraform. (iam, cloudwatch, lambda, ssm, s3).
- Developed various GoLang micro-services focused on integration with AWS, Microsoft, and Safenet APIs.
- Deployed Serverless website using CodeStar, CodeCommit, CodeBuild.
- CodePipeline, S3, Lambda (GoLang), API Gateway, CloudFront.
- Engineered Kubernetes cluster for streaming applications using X11 over SSH.
- Engineered Appstream 2.0 solution to provide multi-user application streaming over HTML5.
- Integrated Amazon SSM solution to provide Equipment inventory and Patch compliance.
- Engineered API Gateway to provide equipment info from DynamoDB via Lambda.
- Engineered AMI factory using EC2 Simple Systems Manager.
- Automated system states for Linux and Windows servers using SaltStack.
- Developed various shell / python scripts to automate AWS maintenance, rotate/share AMIs, bootstrap servers, identify non-compliant servers.
- Deployed AWS Elastic Container Service and dockerized various services.
- Audited security of web-services and ensured they followed PKI best practices.
- Researched and created proof of concepts for latest AWS services for consideration of environment integration.
- Engineered SSSD Central Authentication for all Linux servers in the environment.

## October/2011 – September/2016, Engineering Solutions, Inc. *Lead Linux Engineer*

- Provided leadership, training and project management for 3 PKI Engineers
- Provided subject matter expert guidance for customers interfacing with PKI Technologies
- Designed technical and operational security components by integrating Elasticseach, Logstash, and Kibana to obtain high level analytical view of the information service
- Lead development of enterprise revocation service security architecture.
- Lead enterprise revocation service through certification and accreditation.
- Accredited and deployed servers via physical, virtual, and cloud based mediums
- Developed multiple tools enabling admins and developers to interface with PKI technologies
- Coordinated PKI configurations with desktop providers and software distribution centers.
- Recommended physical, administrative and technical controls to ensure high availability of enterprise PKI service using BIG-IP F5's.
- Recommended and implemented Intrusion detection, access control, and auditing of PKI services.
- Lead security planning, assessment, and risk management activities for PKI services using DISA STIGs, Retina, Nessus technologies.
- Provided system security engineering guidance to Enterprise Lync/Desktop server teams as a subject matter expert in certificate revocation technologies.
- Interacted with high-level stakeholders of Engineering Review Board defining standard OCSP policies and objectives ensuring availability across the enterprise

## June/2010 – September/2011 (1.2 yrs), Ellicott City MD *Technical Consultant*

- Provided guidance on using technology to enhance business productivity.
  Resolved issues with mobile devices, desktop, printers, software, and network appliances.
- Provided Hands on training with new hardware and software technologies.
- Participated in multiple Cyber challenges incorporating computer defense, offense, and forensic strategies. Implementing STIGs, and performing vulnerability assessments with Nessus. Launching exploits with metasploit and armitage, and using tools like Sleuth to perform data recovery.
- Attended Hacker Space events frequently, including seminars, presenting at conferences, and entering capture the flag challenges.
- Attended various classes related to network security: VPN, IDS, Firewall, Pentesting, Cisco, Python, Oracle

# June/2004 – June/2010 (6.0 yrs), US Air Force (Eglin AFB, FL) Systems Engineer

- Technical architect for missions, determined mission requirements, allocated communications equipment (telco, network devices, terminals, servers, crypto), developed proof on concept configurations and provided subject matter expert guidance to deployment teams.
- Provided cryptography solutions for missions, key issuance, renewal, and application.
- Developed scripts allowing air traffic weapons operators automate common tasks
- Provided computer systems support for squadron. Installed software, fixed connectivity issues, diagnosed hardware issues.

### June/1998 – September/2002 (4.2 yrs), Self Employed (Laurel, MD) System Administrator

- Managed website via redhat 5 (Hurricane) linux server running apache
- Managed windows domain services including active directory, dhcp, dns.IIS
- Built and configured windows 98 desktops.
- Resolved hardware issues with computers, printers, telephones and fax machines.
- Built cat-5 cables, ran wires, and diagnosed network connectivity issues.
- Installed and configured Internet Service Provider Routers
- Configured Internet connection sharing and Home networking
- Assisted developers with testing software releases.
- Performed website development for 4 websites using dreamweaver
- Developed various tools using visual basic.

#### **EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS**

Many hours of Self Study, security conferences, podcasts 1998 - Present Military Technical / On the Job Training 2004-2010 Technical college courses of interest, no degree.

### RECENT CERTIFICATIONS/AWARDS/CLASSES

#### Certifications:

AWS DevOps Professional	V64WBJVKCBR4QGCE	August 2017
AWS Certified Developer	AWS-ADEV-7883	January 2017
(ISC) <sup>2</sup> CISSP	410338	October 2014
CCNA Security	CSCO11709829	July 2010
Network+	COMP001008999716	July 2009
A+	COMP0010621927	February 2002